<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
  ! CCPL HEADER START
  !
  ! This work is licensed under the Creative Commons
  ! Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivs 3.0 Unported License.
  ! To view a copy of this license, visit
  ! http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/
  ! or send a letter to Creative Commons, 444 Castro Street,
  ! Suite 900, Mountain View, California, 94041, USA.
  !
  ! You can also obtain a copy of the license at
  ! legal-notices/CC-BY-NC-ND.txt.
  ! See the License for the specific language governing permissions
  ! and limitations under the License.
  !
  ! If applicable, add the following below this CCPL HEADER, with the fields
  ! enclosed by brackets "[]" replaced with your own identifying information:
  !      Portions Copyright [yyyy] [name of copyright owner]
  !
  ! CCPL HEADER END
  !
  !      Copyright 2013-2015 ForgeRock AS
  !
-->
<appendix xml:id='appendix-options'
          xmlns='http://docbook.org/ns/docbook'
          version='5.0' xml:lang='en'
          xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance'
          xsi:schemaLocation='http://docbook.org/ns/docbook
 http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd'
          xmlns:xlink='http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink'>

 <title>OpenICF Operation Options</title>

 <para>
  This chapter describes all of the predefined operation options by the OpenICF
  framework, along with notes about their use. Specific connectors
  may support only a subset of these options.
 </para>

    <section xml:id="operation-option-scope">
        <title>Scope</title>
        <para>
            An option to use with Search (in conjunction with <link linkend="operation-option-container">Container</link>) that specifies how far
            beneath the specified container to search. Must be one of the following values:
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>SCOPE_OBJECT</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>SCOPE_ONE_LEVEL</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>SCOPE_SUBTREE</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="operation-option-container">
        <title>Container</title>
        <para>
            An option to use with Search that specifies the container under which to perform the search. Must be of type QualifiedUid. Should be
            implemented for those object classes whose ObjectClassInfo.isContainer() returns true.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="operation-option-run-as-user">
        <title>Run as User</title>
        <para>
            An option to use with Script on Resource and possibly others that specifies an account under which to execute the script/operation. The specified
            account will appear to have performed any action that the script/operation performs.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="operation-option-run-with-password">
        <title>Run with Password</title>
        <para>
            An option to use with Script on Resource and possibly others that specifies a password under which to execute the script/operation.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="operation-option-attributes-to-get">
        <title>Attributes to Get</title>
        <para>
            Determines which attributes to retrieve during Search and Sync.
            This option overrides the default behavior, which is for the connector to return exactly the set of
            attributes that are identified as returned by default in the schema for that connector.

            This option allows a client application to request additional attributes that would not otherwise not be
            returned (generally because such attributes are more expensive for a connector to fetch and to format)
            and/or to request only a subset of the attributes that would normally be returned.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="operation-option-paged-results-cookie">
        <title>Paged Results Cookie</title>
        <para>
            An option to use with Search that specifies an opaque cookie which is used by the connector to track its position in the set of query
            results.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="operation-option-paged-results-offset">
        <title>Paged Results Offset</title>
        <para>
            An option to use with Search that specifies the index within the result set of the first result which should be returned.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="operation-option-page-size">
        <title>Page Size</title>
        <para>
            An option to use with Search that specifies the requested page results page size.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="operation-option-sort-keys">
        <title>Sort Keys</title>
        <para>
            An option to use with Search that specifies the sort keys which should be used for ordering the ConnectorObject returned by search
            request.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="operation-option-fail-on-error">
        <title>Fail on Error</title>
        <para>
            This option is used with the Batch operation, to specify whether the batch process should be aborted when the first error is encountered.
            The default behavior is to continue processing regardless of errors.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="operation-option-require-serial">
        <title>Require Serial</title>
        <para>
            This option instructs the connector to execute batched requests in a serial manner if possible. 
            The default behavior of the Batch operation is to execute requests in parallel, 
            for speed and efficiency. In either case the task ID must be reflected in the response for each task,
            so that tasks can be correctly reordered.
        </para>
    </section>

</appendix>
